Guide to the A. Henry Detweiler papers, [ca. 1924]-1970.
Detweiler, A. Henry papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
A. Henry Detweiler papers, [ca. 1924]-1970.
15-2-1363
Detweiler, A. Henry
20 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, financial records, manuscripts, printed material, publications, maps, architectural plans, and artwork.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include student drawings, business and personal correspondence, subject files, account books, diaries, postcards, clippings, notebooks, lecture slides, course material and exams, notes and drafts of articles, reports, printed material concerning Sardis, pamphlets, maps, charts, blueprints, floor plans, and other material pertaining to Detweiler's work at Cornell, the American Schools of Oriental Research, history of architecture, and archaeological field work.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Architect, archaeologist, professor of architecture.
Albert Henry Detweiler received a bachelor's degree in architecture in 1930 from the University of Pennsylvania. In the early 1930s he became involved with the American Schools of Oriental Research, with which he maintained a lifelong affiliation. He joined the Cornell University faculty in 1939, was appointed associate dean of the College of Architecture in 1956, and as chairman of the Committee on Student Conduct was active in the organization of a new judicial system at Cornell. In 1957 Professor Detweiler joined George M. A. Hanfmann of Harvard in organizing the archaeological exploration of Sardis in Turkey under the aegis of the American Schools of Oriental Research. Detweiler was also field archaeologist at a number of famous Near Eastern excavations, was interested in architectural conservation and restoration, and studied architectural history in Europe, including study of the origins of Christian architecture while a Guggenheim Fellow in 1961-1962. He was active in professional organizations, including the Society of Architectural Historians and the American Institute of Architects.
Letter from Henry Detweiler to Deane W. Malott about Detweiler's participation in the 600th anniversary of the founding of the University of Pavia, 1961.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include student drawings, business and personal correspondence, subject files, account books, diaries, postcards, clippings, notebooks, lecture slides, course material and exams, notes and drafts of articles, reports, printed material concerning Sardis, pamphlets, maps, charts, blueprints, floor plans, and other material pertaining to Detweiler's work at Cornell, the American Schools of Oriental Research, history of architecture, and archaeological field work. Also, approximately 120 condolence letters written to Catharine Bunnell Detweiler after the death of her husband.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Detweiler, A. Henry, 1906-1970.; Detweiler, Catharine Bunnell; Detweiler, Catharine Bunnell.; American Schools of Oriental Research; American Schools of Oriental Research.; Archaeological Exploration of Sardis (Program); Archaeological Exploration of Sardis (Program); Cornell University. College of Architecture, Art, and Planning -- Faculty.; Cornell University. College of Architecture, Art, and Planning
Subjects:
Archaeological expeditions.; Architecture.; Architects.; Architectural historians.; Archaeological expeditions; Architects; Architecture; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Blueprints.; Charts.; Maps.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. American School of Oriental Research (ASOR) Material
Series II. Architecture and Course Materials
Series III. Correspondence
Series IV. General Documents and Material
Series V. American Research Institute in Turkey (ARIT) Materials
Series VI. American Research Center in Egypt (ARCE) Materials
Series VII. American Institute for Architects (AIA) Materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. American School of Oriental Research (ASOR) Material
  - ASOR Correspondence on New Jerusalem Building, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ASOR Correspondence and Invoices, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ASOR Correspondence and Invoices, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ASOR Members, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ASOR Invoices, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ASOR USAID Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ASOR/USAID Contract and Related Materials, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ASOR/USAID Contract, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ASOR Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ASOR Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ASOR Financial Documents, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Paul W. Lapp ASOR Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - USAID Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ASOR Inspection Trip, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ASOR Jerusalem School Correspondence, 1955-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ASOR Invoices, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ASOR Carl Kraeling Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ASOR Payroll, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ASOR Payroll, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ASOR Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ASOR Prospective Personnel, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - ASOR Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - ASOR Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - ASOR Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - ASOR Correspondence, 1966- 1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - ASOR/USAID Progress Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - USAID Quarterly Report, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - USAID to Jordan Notes, 1965-07-26-1965-08-14 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Trip to Jerusalem Notes, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1934-1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1949-1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1955-1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1930-1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ASOR Bulletins, 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sardis Excavation Materials/News, 1958-1965 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Sardis Excavation News, 1958-1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - ASOR Reports, 1960-1969 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - ASOR Reports, 1960-1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Sardis Excavation Notes, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Diaries of Jerash Excavations, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, 1930-1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - ASOR Correspondence- A, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - ASOR Financial Records- Ithaca, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - ASOR Financial Records- Jerusalem, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - ASOR Employment Applications, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - ASOR Correspondence- B, 1950-1954 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - ASOR Financial Records, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - ASOR Correspondence- C, 1952-1955 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - ASOR Correspondence- Jerusalem School, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - ASOR Correspondence- D-G, 1950-1954 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - ASOR Correspondence- H-J, 1942-1953 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Jerusalem Trip Materials, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Jericho Dig Materials, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Fellowship to Israel, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - ASOR Correspondence- K, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence from Kathleen Kenyon (Jericho Dig), 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - ASOR Correspondence- M, 1952-1955 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - ASOR Correspondence- N+L, 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - ASOR Correspondence- G-Q, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - ASOR Publicity, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - ASOR Correspondence- R, 1951-1955 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - ASOR Correspondence- S, 1951-1955 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ASOR Correspondence- T, 1951-1954 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - ASOR Annual Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - ASOR Correspondence- U-Z, 1951-1954 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ASOR Correspondence- Kraeling, 1946-1952 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - ASOR AID Trustees, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - USAID Correspondence, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Films and Slides Info, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - ASOR Periodicals, 1939-1941 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series II. Architecture and Course Materials
  - Carnegie Foundation: Color Slide Project, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Trip to Cali, Colombia, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1957-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Institute of Architects Meeting, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Institute of Architects of Gatlinburg Conference, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - New York City Program, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation Materials, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - College of Architecture Curriculum Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - French Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - French Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Italian Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Italian Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Italian Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - French Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - English Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Spain, Netherlands, Germany, and Scandinavia Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dutch, German, English Colonial Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - English Renaissance Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Late English Colonial Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - French Gothic Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Italian and Spanish Gothic Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Gothic Revival Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - English and German Gothic Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - European and American Eclecticism Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Classic Revival in the US Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Spanish and French Colonies in America Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Romanesque in England Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Romanesque in France Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Romanesque in Germany, Scandinavia, and Spain Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - History of Engineering in Architecture Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Art Nouveau 20th Century Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - ARCH 407 Syllabus, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ARCH 404 Syllabus, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ARCH 405 Syllabus, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Exams, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Sardis Newspaper Clippings, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ARCH 48 Special Lecture, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Professional Practice Notes ARCH 47, 1929-05-31 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Professional Practice Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Unpublished Architecture Paper, Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Siena and Orvieto Charts of Historic Events, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Notes on Business and Architecture Styles, 1940-1949 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Scroll Presented to AHD in Puerto Rico, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Lectures Notes: Classical Architecture, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Notes: Historical City Planning, 1948-1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Notes: Roman Architecture, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Notes: Greek Architecture, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Notes: Roman Architecture I, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Notes: Classical Greece, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lecture Notes: Romanesque Architecture, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes: Egyptian Architecture, Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Notes: Islamic Architecture, Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - History of Architecture 407 Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - History of Architecture 407 Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - History of Architecture 408 Papers, 1955-1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - History of Architecture 408 Papers, 1950-1953 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Modern Architecture Papers, Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - History of Architecture 413 Papers, 1946-1948 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - History of Architecture 413 Exams, 1939-1943 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Byzantine Architecture, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - French and Roman Architecture, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - History of Architecture 407 Papers, 1939-1951 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - History of Architecture 412 Papers, 1947-1950 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - History of Architecture 400 Papers, 1963-1969 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - History of Architecture 400 Exams, 1952-1961 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - History of Architecture 401 Papers, 1952-1961 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - History of Architecture 401 Papers, 1949-1960 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - History of Architecture 401 Exams, 1949-1956 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - History of Architecture 406 Papers, 1956-1960 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Architecture 406 Exams, 1948-1958 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Architecture 406 Prelims, 1948-1958 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Architecture 406 Prelims, 1949-1958 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - New History Course 406 Notes, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - History of Architecture 406 Prelims, 1940-1950 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - History of Architecture 411 Exams, 1940-1947 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - History of Architecture 406 Exams, 1951-1958 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - History of Architecture 404 Lectures, 1952-1958 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - History of Architecture 404 Lectures, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - History of Architecture 404 Prelims, 1947-1956 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - History of Architecture 404 Prelims, 1947-1958 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - History of Architecture 404 Prelims, 1950-1959 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - History of Architecture 404 Exams, 1948-1959 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - History of Architecture 404 Exams, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - History of Architecture 405 Exams, 1948-1960 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - History of Architecture 405 Finals, 1948-1953 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Architecture 700: History of City Planning, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - History of Architecture 410 Exams, 1928-1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - History of Architecture 411 Assignments, 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - History of Architecture 411 Reading List, 1942-1946 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - History of Architecture 412 Reading List, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - History of Architecture 412 Reading List, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - History of Architecture 411 Assignments, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - History of Architecture 412 Reading List, 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - History of Architecture 411 Seating Charts, 1939-1941 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - History of Architecture 410 Correspondence, 1939-1944 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - History of Architecture 471 Class Meetings, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Photos of Colombia, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - History of American and Contemporary Art Syllabus Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - History of Architecture 412 Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - History of Architecture 412 Notes, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - History of Architecture 412 Notes, 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Papers from Detweiler's School Career, 1910-1928 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - History of Architecture 412 Notes, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - History of Architecture 413 American Architecture Notes, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Periodicals, 1934-1936 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Architecture Drawings, Undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Periodicals, 1914-1932 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Cornell Buildings Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous American Architecture Notes, 1933-1942 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Architecture 404 Notes, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - History of Architecture 411 Notes, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Ithaca Architecture, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Architecture Notes, 1926-1928 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Admissions Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Admissions Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Architecture History 400-401, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Articles- Misc., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bollinger Foundation, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Constituent Assembly, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Special Education Projects (COSEP), 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Dura Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Environmental Values, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Minutes- Department of Architecture, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence O-P, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence N, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence M, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Lectures Correspondence, 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence G, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - State Department Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence S, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence w/ William L. Reed, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence R, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1926-1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - AHD- Personal Correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - George V Egge Jr and Fowler Hamilton Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Business Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Business Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Business Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence w/ William L. Reed, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - AHD- Personal Correspondence, 1926-1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Lists, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence T, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence U-V, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Villa Serbelloni Correspondence, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence W, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- Prescott Williams, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Department of Archaeology/Anthropology Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- G. Ernest Wright, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1930-1933 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Business Correspondence, 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-06-25 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1952-1970 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Condolence Letters to Catherine Detweiler, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Condolence Letters to Catherine Detweiler, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Condolence Letters to Catherine Detweiler, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Condolence Letters to Catherine Detweiler, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Russell and Sarah Wright Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - ARCE and Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- B, 1947-1954 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- C-F, 1941-1955 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Gifts to the University, 1945-1950 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- G-J, 1946-1955 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- K-M, 1945-1955 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Fellowship Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- Mc-O, 1941-1955 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- P-R, 1942-1955 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- S-T, 1947-1955 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Sabbatical Leave, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- U-W, 1944-1955 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell Periodicals, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Extra Reports: European Tour, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Library Correspondence, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Scotland Fuel Efficiency Conference, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence and Site Plans- Ann Perkins, 1950-1974; Site Plan of Roman building at Dura? (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Electronics Info, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Electronics Info and Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence- Albright, 1946-1954 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Notes, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- C, 1965-1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Invoices, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- F-H, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Askell Lectures Correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Recommendation Letter, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - International Council of Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - International Council of Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- G-M, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- N-S, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Registrar's Office Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Sardis Correspondence, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Space Committee Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - University Lecture Committee Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- W, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence- Dr. Yadin, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence- A.H. Detweiler to C.S. Detweiler, 1947; Note: Important for English Research Project (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence- A.H. Detweiler to C.S. Detweiler, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Notes on Middle Eastern Archaeology, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Manual for Archaeological Excavation, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence- A.H. Detweiler to C.S. Detweiler, 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence- A.H. Detweiler to C.S. Detweiler, 1936-1939 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence- A.H. Detweiler to C.S. Detweiler, 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence- A.H.D. to Harbeson, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 42)
- Series IV. General Documents and Material
  - Danforth Lectures, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Travel Vouchers, 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Campus Store Board of Directors Notes, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Preservation of Environmental Values on the Campus, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - AHD Course Materials, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Slide Library, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Registration and Scheduling Committee Meetings, 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Grading Committee, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Harvard Ad Hoc Committee, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jacob Hirsch Estate, 1952-1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Visual Aides, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Work Project Proposals, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Slide Library, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Campus Store Article, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)